portada-online.com 2019-04-16

# Privacy Policy » Portada

At Portada we recognize that privacy is important. This Privacy Policy applies to all of the products, services and websites offered by Portada. Portada adheres to the US Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of Notice, Choice, Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity, Access and Enforcement. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to [contact us](https://www.portada-online.com/marketingtohispanics/contact-portada/) through our website or write to us at

Portada  
40 West 38th Street, 5th Floor  
NY, NY 10018  
USA

### AdRoll and Partners

As you browse Portada-Online.com, mercadotecnia.Portada-Online.com, latam.Portada-Online.com, advertising cookies will be placed on your computer so that we can understand what you are interested in. Our display advertising partner, AdRoll, then enables us to present you with retargeting advertising on other sites based on your previous interaction with Portada-Online.com, mercadotecnia.Portada-Online.com, latam.Portada-Online.com. The techniques our partners employ do not collect personal information such as your name, email address, postal address or telephone number. You can [visit this page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) to opt out of AdRoll and their partners’ targeted advertising.

### Information we collect and how we use it

A substantial part of the content posted on our website does not  require you to register for an account or provide any personal information to us. However, in order to provide our full range of services (Free E-newsletters, Paid Subscriptions to publications, online content, databases, Event tickets) we may collect the following types of information:

  * **Information you provide** – When you sign up for a Portada Account for a Portada service or promotion that requires registration, we ask you for personal information (such as your name, email address and an account password). For certain services, such as Paid Subscriptions, Databases and/or Event Tickets, we also request credit card or other payment account information which we maintain in encrypted form on secure servers. We may combine the information you submit under your account with information from other Portada services in order to provide you with a better experience and to improve the quality of our services. For certain services, we may give you the opportunity to opt out of combining such information.
  * **Cookies** – When you visit Portada, we send one or more cookies – a small file containing a string of characters – to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service by storing user preferences and tracking user trends, such as how people search. Portada also uses cookies in its advertising services to help advertisers and publishers serve and manage ads across the web. We may set a cookie in your browser when you visit a website and view or click on an ad supported by Portada’s advertising services.
  * **Log information** – When you access Portada services, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website. These server may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser.
  * **User communications** – When you send email or other communications to Portada, we may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve our services.
  * **Links** – Portada may present links in a format that enables us to keep track of whether these links have been followed. We use this information to improve the quality of our search technology, customized content and advertising. For more information about links and redirected URLs, please see our [F](http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy_glossary.html#urls)AQ[s](http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy_glossary.html#urls).

Portada only processes personal information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy and/or the supplementary privacy notices for specific services. In addition to the above, such purposes include:

  * Auditing, research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our services;
  * Ensuring the technical functioning of our websites/products
  * Developing new services such as databases.

### Choices for personal information

When you sign up for a particular service that requires registration, we ask you to provide personal information.  By submitting this information, we ask you to confirm that you are  only acting for your  own e-mail account, or one for which you have express authority to submit this request.

We will not collect or use information for purposes other than those described in this Privacy Policy and/or in the supplementary service privacy notices, unless we have obtained your prior consent.

Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent.

You can decline to submit personal information to any of our services, in which case Portada may not be able to provide those services to you.

### Information sharing

Portada only shares personal information with other companies or individuals outside of Portada in the following limited circumstances:

  * Once the subscription (Free E-newsletters, Paid Subscriptions, Databases, Event Tickets)  is confirmed, subscribers may get e-mails from third parties that are related to the areas the subscriber opted into.

If Portada becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of its assets, we will provide notice before personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

We may share with third parties certain pieces of such as the number of users who searched for a particular term, for example, or how many users clicked on a particular advertisement. Such information does not identify you individually.

Please contact us at the address below for any additional questions about the management or use of personal data.

Portada  
40 W. 38th Street , Fifth Floor  
NY, NY 10018

### Information security

We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data.

We restrict access to personal information to Portada employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations.

### Data integrity

Portada processes personal information only for the purposes for which it was collected and in accordance with this Privacy Policy or any applicable service-specific privacy notice. We review our data collection, storage and processing practices to ensure that we only collect, store and process the personal information needed to provide or improve our services. We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we process is accurate, complete, and current, but we depend on our users to update or correct their personal information whenever necessary.

### Accessing and updating personal information

When you use Portada services, we make good faith efforts to provide you with access to your personal information and either to correct this data if it is inaccurate or to delete such data at your request if it is not otherwise required to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes. You can edit, modify and/or delete your information by logging in to the website (www.portada-online.com) and accessing the “Account” area of our website. Once in there, click on “Profile” and  edit, modify and/or delete your personal information.

### Enforcement

Portada regularly reviews its compliance with this Privacy Policy. Please feel free to direct any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy or Portada’s treatment of personal information by [contacting us](https://www.portada-online.com/marketingtohispanics/contact-portada/) through this web site or by writing to us at

Portada  
40 West 38th Street, 5th Floor  
NY, NY 10018  
USA

When we receive formal written complaints at this address, it is Portada’s policy to contact the complaining user regarding his or her concerns. We will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that cannot be resolved between Portada and an individual.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Please note that this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will not reduce your rights under this Privacy Policy without your explicit consent, and we expect most such changes will be minor. Regardless, we will post any Privacy Policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice (including, for certain services, email notification of Privacy Policy changes).

If you have any additional questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us any time through this web site or at

Portada  
40 West 38th Street, 5th Floor  
NY, NY 10018  
USA
